# **Hyalen Moreira Caldeira**

Portfolio: Main Portfolio & Under Development

Phone: Email: LinkedIn: GitHub:

+1 (909) 234 7007 - Dublin, OH hyalen@amail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/hyalen https://aithub.com/hyalen-moreira

## **ABOUT**

A **Software Engineer** with 6+ years of experience, I have **Software Development** (Java/Spring, Angular/React) and Cloud experience. I enjoy developing software from the ground up, learning new technologies, refactoring legacy code and ensuring the satisfaction of the companies I work for. With an open-mind and a drive to learn, my goal in life is to develop software that will advance humanity as well as inspire the next generation of programmers.

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## Accenture – as a Software Engineer

Columbus/OH, March 2019 - Current

- Consulted some big companies as part of its *Full Stack Engineer* & *Cloud* team. Built Micro-Frontend applications with *Java, Spring Boot* and *Angular* to run on top of legacy systems, extracting existent functionalities and/or implementing new ones. Worked as a *Full-Stack Engineer*, designing features, building *RESTful APIs*, migrating legacy systems to the new Microservice/Micro-Frontend architecture, creating and executing *Unit Tests*;
- Actively helping with internal knowledge dissemination, promoting internal technical events, mentoring
   *Java/Spring Boot* and *Angular* apprentices, writing blog posts for Accenture Code's community, developing
   internal projects to fill in AC's necessities and trying out new technologies;
- Acted as an **AWS Cloud Software Engineer** to innovate a service that enhances a big tech and entertainment company (in partnership with a large bank) customers delivery experience;
- **DevOps** & **Continuous Integration Engineer** for internal, regional and international projects. I bring projects to comply with the latest **Continuous Integration** and **Continuous Delivery** practices.

**Key achievement**: Responsible for maintaining and developing new features for the company's main website. Contributed to migrate *Monolithics* applications to *Microservice* and *Cloud* architecture. Delivered apps with 100% on-time record and only minimal updates, following *Agile* methodologies and applying *XP* best practices. Acted as an *Anchor* helping new Engineers to increase their skills and ensuring that they follow best development practices.

Skills: Java, Spring Boot, TypeScript, JavaScript, Angular, Jasmine/Karma, Git, RESTful, Agile, CI/CD

# cFive – as a Software Engineer

Laguna Hills/CA, June 2018 - March 2019

- Spring Security SAML, Spring Boot, Java Designed, architected and developed a security model (through Microservice Architecture) to allow access to the LA County main system using Microsoft AAD/MIM. The system is accessed by government departments such as the FBI, Police Department, among others. This project is an implementation of a SAML 2.0 Service Provider, completely built on Spring Framework. A web solution devised for Federated Authentication by integrating Spring Boot and Spring Security SAML. The configuration has been completely defined using Java annotations (no XML);
- Full Stack Developer (Java, Jersey, JPA, React/Next, TypeScript, Bootstrap, HTML and CSS).

# Conversant – as a Software Engineer

Westlake Village/CA, June 2017 - January 2018

- Java, Spring Boot, Spring MVC, RESTful APIs and Hibernate Write code in an Agile environment for an online Ad Network company's Java API. Add server-side support for new SaaS UI features, address bug tickets in legacy system with focus on TDD and delivered quality projects that have been well-received;
- **Spring Cloud** Implemented from scratch a central config server where all configurable parameters of applications are written version controlled. The benefit of a central config server is that if we change a property for an app, it can reflect that on the fly without redeploying the app. The solution maintains all properties of all environments (development, staging and production), and if any properties are changed, it will pick up the changes and reflect them without an application rebuild or restart;
- Hazelcast and Spring AOP Implemented a distributed cache to lock correlated services being treated at the same time among different servers;
- Our tests are done in *Groovy* with *Spock*, but eventually I added the use of an in-memory *H2* database for testing
  models rapidly and without need for a network connection as we would require with integration tests; Other
  responsibilities include Managing Releases, improving release methods/tools and maintaining an old *Java* based
  project that keeps data synchronized between our local database and an external data store.

## **CERTIFICATES**

- CKAD Certified Kubernetes Application Developer;
- HashCorp Certified Terraform Associate;
- AWS Certified SysOps Administrator;
- AWS Certified Developer Associate;
- CFCD Cloud Foundry Certified Developer;
- React (by Udacity), San Francisco CA 2017.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- **Proficient in:** Java/Spring; **Familiar with**: Angular, React, TypeScript/JavaScript;
- Interest: Backend, Front-End, Full Stack Development;
- **AWS**: IAM, EKS, VPC, EC2, S3, Lambda, API Gateway, CodeCommit, CodeBuild, CodePipeline, CloudFormation, Elastic Beanstalk, DynamoDB, CloudWatch, EventBridge, StepFunction and others
- Architecture/Standards: JEE, Microservices, JAX-RS, JAX-WS, Design Patterns, OOP, object and data modeling;
- Test Tools: JUnit, Karate, Spock, Selenium, Jasmine/Karma; Data Interchange: JSON, XML;
- Paradigms: Agile, SCRUM/XP, TDD, CI/CD processes, DDD (Domain Driven Design);
- Others: Terraform, Gradle, Maven, Kubernetes, NoSQL, Relational Database (Oracle/MySQL/PostgreSQL), Docker, Helm, Istio, Ansible, Git, Perforce, Stash, Bamboo, Jenkins, Nexus, Swagger, Tomcat, Jersey, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, SAP PI/PO, Linux/UNIX, JSP/Servlet.

## **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS**

- Course: Software Engineering University: Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais Brazil, 2004/03 to 2005/08;
- Course: Technology in Data Processing University: Centro Universitário UNA Brazil, 2000.

## **LANGUAGES**

- Portuguese Native language;
- English and Spanish Professional working proficiency.